<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Accueil on Vincent Nicolas</title>
    <link>alainncls.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Accueil on Vincent Nicolas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>fr-fr</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 18:56:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="alainncls.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Documentaire radio</title>
      <link>alainncls.github.io/projects/documentaire-radio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 15:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>alainncls.github.io/projects/documentaire-radio/</guid>
      <description>Documentaire réalisé pour Radio Mille-Pattes dans le cadre de l&amp;rsquo;émission Soul Brothers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installation interactive</title>
      <link>alainncls.github.io/projects/installation-interactive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 15:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>alainncls.github.io/projects/installation-interactive/</guid>
      <description>CONTACT est le projet d’installation clôturant la spécialité &amp;ldquo;Scénographie sonore&amp;rdquo; des étudiants de la promotion Son 2020 de l’École nationale supérieure Louis-Lumière. Il a été présenté en novembre 2019 à la Muse en Circuit, centre national de création musicale à Alfortville (94, France).
Présentation PDF</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enregistrement Clarinette</title>
      <link>alainncls.github.io/projects/enregistrement-clarinette/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 15:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>alainncls.github.io/projects/enregistrement-clarinette/</guid>
      <description>Enregistré à l&amp;rsquo;ENS Louis-Lumière en juin 2019 Ingénieur du Son : Vincent Nicolas Assistant Ingénieur du Son : Martin Guesney Cette vidéo est à usage exclusivement non-commercial Audio MP3 haute qualité 320 kbps</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forcing Visits to use SSL</title>
      <link>alainncls.github.io/blog/force-ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 14:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>alainncls.github.io/blog/force-ssl/</guid>
      <description>Intro Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether it&amp;rsquo;s a CakePHP app for a client, your own personal CMS, or any other web based application. If your passing around passwords or other sensitive info you should really implement SSL. SSL provides 2 main perks to your visitors.
 First it encrypts all communication that flies across the web. This prevents curious or devious billies from getting your secrets. Secondly it ensures to the user that your server is in fact who it claims, and not a nasty &amp;lsquo;man in the middle&amp;rdquo; attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Results</title>
      <link>alainncls.github.io/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>alainncls.github.io/search/</guid>
      <description>This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related search layout template.
No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html
Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.
This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js
Initial setup Search depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml
[outputs] home = [&amp;#34;HTML&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;JSON&amp;#34;] Searching additional fileds To search additional fields defined in front matter, you must add it in 2 places.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>