<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Alain Nicolas</title><link>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Alain Nicolas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lineaster</title><link>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/lineaster/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/lineaster/</guid><description>The context As part of the launch of its ZK-EVM type network, Consensys wanted to organize an event to invite as many users as possible to interact with the network. Indeed, it was both about making it known, and testing its ability to support a large number of users.
But to bring a large number of testers, they needed a reason to come. That’s why, during the &amp;#34;Testnet Voyage&amp;#34;, Consensys chose to rely on applications around DeFi, but also identity with the ENS protocol, or the Lens protocol for the social aspect.</description></item><item><title>Crypto-lending Platform</title><link>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/crypto-lending/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/crypto-lending/</guid><description>The client For confidentiality reasons, the name of this client cannot be revealed. They are a company already well established in the web3 domain, looking to expand their reach.
The project The project involves the creation of a centralized cryptocurrency lending platform, against collateral provided by users.
Therefore, it was necessary to create a user interface that is understandable and clear enough to attract the largest number, but also to provide all the standard features in this type of application.</description></item><item><title>RoxTheCasbah</title><link>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/roxthecasbah/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 15:00:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/roxthecasbah/</guid><description>The context Creation of a blog for my partner, RoxTheCasbah, to share her passion for knitting and sewing.
The technical solution The first version The first version of the site used Ghost, a complete blogging solution competing with WordPress. Based on an open-source and free tool, the blog was hosted on a small AWS machine.
The second version In January 2021, I chose to switch to a static site generator, Hugo, in order to be able to host the generated pages for free.</description></item><item><title>This Site</title><link>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/this-site/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 15:00:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/this-site/</guid><description>Context Creation of this site to introduce myself and share my passions.
My first desire was to showcase my skills in a more controlled way than, for example, on LinkedIn. Similarly, in order to efficiently centralize the articles I have written on Medium or Talan Labs&amp;#39; blog, I needed a blog.
Technical Solution The Tool This site is designed using a static site generator, Hugo, and hosted for free thanks to &amp;#34;GitHub Pages&amp;#34; service.</description></item><item><title>Atelier 58</title><link>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/atelier-58/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/atelier-58/</guid><description>The context Creation of the showcase site for the hair salon &amp;#34;Atelier 58&amp;#34; in Paris.
The technical solution Tools This site is designed using a static site generator, Hugo.
Integration of the Planity service for making appointments.
Implementation of navigation statistics tracking via Insights.
Theme In order to save time, but also to best meet the needs of such a business, I started from the theme &amp;#34;Hugo Hero Theme&amp;#34;.</description></item><item><title>BNP CIB - Blockchain-as-a-Service</title><link>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/bnp-blockchain/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/bnp-blockchain/</guid><description>The Client As a major player in the banking sector, BNP Paribas must stay at the forefront of available technologies. This is how blockchain and DLT technologies have become essential.
Like many large companies, BNP is divided into several entities that can all participate in the same project, which is not without raising challenges around collaboration.
The Project To allow all BNP entities to experiment on the blockchain before easily joining a decentralized consortium, it was necessary to make accessible technologies that we can qualify as exotic.</description></item><item><title>Coface</title><link>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/coface/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/coface/</guid><description>The client Coface is a major player in credit insurance. In order to remain competitive and gain new market share, the company needs to regularly offer new software products and solutions to its customers.
The project Optimization and evolution of a web application (Cofanet Policy Master &amp;amp; Cofanet Policy Master Administration) for paying customers.
To achieve this, a technical refactoring of the project architecture and a redesign of the major features of the application were needed.</description></item><item><title>e-Paye</title><link>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/epaye/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/epaye/</guid><description>The client e-Paye develops software dedicated to HRIS: payroll, digital safe, HR management, interview management, etc.
The project Among the e-Paye modules, the one allowing the generation of payslips is particularly important and complex. Indeed, it must take into account sometimes changing legislation, but also be able to generate a large number of payslips in a short amount of time.
Technical stack Client-side JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Ajax
Server-side Spring (Core, MVC, Security, Data)</description></item><item><title>EDF Commerce - Craftsmanship Evangelization</title><link>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/edf/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/edf/</guid><description>The client EDF Commerce’s Digital Department has a dedicated team for PoC realization for the group’s various businesses.
The mission The mission is to evangelize on the concepts of craftsmanship and industrialize the best practices to be implemented. This is how I was able to initiate the implementation of the first CI/CD pipelines via GitLab and Jenkins, but also push the use of SonarQube for code quality monitoring and Nexus for depositing generated artifacts.</description></item><item><title>FuturMaster - Calibrate Model</title><link>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/futurmaster-calibrate-model/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/futurmaster-calibrate-model/</guid><description>The Client FuturMaster, a software editor specializing in supply chain management, called on Talan Labs to reinforce its development teams and speed up the redesign of its tool suite.
The Project That’s how I became part of the first agile squad, made up of 3 developers, 1 designer and 1 Scrum Master. We were tasked with the redesign of the Calibrate Model module, which aims to display the sales history of a product and simulate its future sales.</description></item><item><title>FuturMaster - Master Data</title><link>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/futurmaster-master-data/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/futurmaster-master-data/</guid><description>Client FuturMaster, a software editor specializing in supply chain management, called upon Talan Labs to strengthen its development teams and accelerate the revamp of its suite of tools.
Project Following the success of the first Talan Labs squad’s intervention at FuturMaster on the Calibrate Model project, we embarked on the revamp of the Master Data module, which centralizes the data repository that feeds the other software suite modules.
In parallel with the development of functional user stories, there are many technical topics to consider, such as a reflection on the future database best suited to the specifics of the objects to be manipulated.</description></item><item><title>Gefco - Opteam</title><link>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/gefco/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/gefco/</guid><description>The client Gefco is a major player in logistics and in particular in the transportation of automotive parts.
The project Development of a scheduling system under constraints.
Technical stack Desktop application Java Swing
Database OracleDB</description></item><item><title>Share2gether</title><link>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/share2gether/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/share2gether/</guid><description>Context Share2Gether aims to create an event organization solution, similar to what Meetup.com offers.
I had the opportunity to share more details about this experience in a dedicated article.
Technical Stack Client Side The front-end is a Vue.js application that communicates with smart contracts deployed on the blockchain using the web3.js library.
Blockchain Side Smart contracts written in Solidity are deployed on an Ethereum blockchain. Standard contracts provided by OpenZeppelin are used.</description></item><item><title>Talan Coin</title><link>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/talan-talancoin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/talan-talancoin/</guid><description>The Context Like all companies, Talan seeks to catalyze collaboration within itself. In addition, Talan wishes to strengthen its unity as a group despite distinct entities and a presence on 4 continents, and develop a horizontal organization far from classic vertical hierarchies.
An internal currency, common to all employees regardless of their location or hierarchical role, makes it possible to find a common point among all the actors in the company.</description></item><item><title>Talan Labs Blog</title><link>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/talan-blog-labs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/talan-blog-labs/</guid><description>Context Maintenance of the Talan Labs blog, writing articles, before a complete overhaul in 2019/2020.
The Talan Labs blog allows for sharing the knowledge of Talan Labs employees.
Technical Solution Legacy version The first version of the site used WordPress, a well-known solution.
Overhaul Given the difficulty of keeping such a site up to date while ensuring its security, we chose to radically change the technology to significantly reduce the attack surface.</description></item><item><title>VINCI Construction Terrassement - VCoin</title><link>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/vct-vcoin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alainnicolas.fr/en/projects/vct-vcoin/</guid><description>The Context After the success of Talan Coin, the VINCI group wanted to experiment with its own version of the application.
This is how we instantiated the VCoin application, with some specific features setting it apart from Talan Coin.
The Technical Stack Client Side Native iOS application
Native Android application
Angular web applications:
Dashboard for statistical tracking and administration
Store for objects and services payable in Talan Coins
Desktop client (not in production)</description></item></channel></rss>